Now before we get started with the actual practice for this lesson let's just go over some some basic
现在，在我们开始本课的实际练习之前，让我们回顾一些基本的
vocabulary.
词汇。
I think you probably know one or two of these words before.
我想你可能以前知道这些词中的一两个。
We've talked certainly a little bit about variation but a variation is basically a another version of
我们已经谈到了一些关于变体的内容，但变体基本上是另一个版本
the same thing.
同样的事情。
If you do a variation of something that means you do it again in a slightly different way whether it's
如果你做了某件事的变体，这意味着你会以稍微不同的方式再次做这件事，无论是
a painting or maybe a dish you're cooking whatever it happens to be a variation means you've taken that
一幅画，或者你正在做的一道菜，无论它碰巧是一种变化，都意味着你已经接受了它
thing and you're going to try to do that same thing but make a couple of small changes.
事情，你会尝试做同样的事情，但做一些小的改变。
So you've made a variation of that.
所以你已经做了一个变体。
And if we have many of those we can say many variations that will make more sense a little bit later
如果我们有很多这样的，我们可以说很多变化，稍后会更有意义
in this lesson with what we're going to do next.
在这节课中，我们接下来要做什么。
OK now liberties Well you might know the word liberty means freedom.
好的，现在自由 好吧，您可能知道“自由”这个词意味着自由。
OK.
好的。
Liberties can mean the plural form of freedom.
自由可以意味着自由的复数形式。
But when I say in this case take liberties we often hear say take liberties.
但是当我在这种情况下说随意，我们经常听到说随意。
That means don't restrict yourself too much to one specific thing.
这意味着不要将自己限制在一件特定的事情上。
So if you take some creative liberties for example when you're doing a variation of a painting maybe
因此，如果你在创作一幅画的变体时采取一些创造性的自由，也许
you're trying to paint a painting similar to a famous painting.
你正在尝试画一幅类似于名画的画。
OK.
好的。
And you might add I don't know an extra flower or you might add some different colors.
你可能会添加我不知道额外的花，或者你可能会添加一些不同的颜色。
That would be taking liberties.
那将是冒犯。
That means just following your following your heart I guess taking some freedom to do what you want
这意味着只要跟随你的心，我想你可以自由地做你想做的事
to do to do what feels right.
做感觉对的事。
OK.
好的。
So that's OK.
所以没关系。
That's what we call taking liberties.
这就是我们所说的放肆。
And when we do today's lesson and the exercises that we're going to talk about today we need to remember
当我们做今天的课程和我们今天要讨论的练习时，我们需要记住
that it's OK to take liberties sometimes taking liberties or doing what we feel might be interesting
放肆是可以的 有时放肆或做我们认为可能有趣的事情
is a good way to explore new types of grammar or explore how we use words it might be also a good way
是探索新语法类型或探索我们如何使用单词的好方法 它可能也是一个好方法
to maybe find new uses of for example vocabulary.
也许找到例如词汇的新用途。
So it actually can be really useful.
所以它实际上非常有用。
All right.
好的。
Now improvisation and we'll talk a little bit more about this at the end or toward the end of the lesson.
现在即兴创作，我们将在课程结束时或接近课程结束时多谈一点。
The short version of this is often improv I and P R O V improv and improv is often related to comedy.
简短的版本通常是即兴表演 I 和 P R O V 即兴表演，即兴表演通常与喜剧有关。
So you might see improv comedy which means that nothing is planned.
所以你可能会看到即兴喜剧，这意味着没有任何计划。
Maybe there's a situation maybe there is a scene but nobody knows what's going to happen.
也许有一种情况，也许有一个场景，但没有人知道会发生什么。
There's no script there's no dialogue.
没有剧本就没有对话。
So you'll see maybe an improv comedy show.
所以你可能会看到一个即兴喜剧节目。
It's very funny because nobody knows what's going to happen.
这很有趣，因为没有人知道会发生什么。
And it's kind of crazy.
这有点疯狂。
Improvisation is this ability to be able to speak naturally and continuously without really thinking
即兴创作是一种无需真正思考就能够自然而连续地说话的能力
carefully about what you're saying.
仔细考虑你在说什么。
And we're going to practice that later on in the lesson.
我们将在本课的后面进行练习。
So I hope these three words are clear and let's go on to our first exercise.
所以我希望这三个词是清楚的，让我们继续我们的第一个练习。